A Guide to the Donald R. Griffin papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA164
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1
  - Hoc-Hut (Box 5, Folder 45)
    Hochbaum, H. Albert - bird banding; Delta Waterfowl Research Station, Canada;. Hockett, Charles S. - Cornell University. Hollander, Peter - Rockefeller University research associate. Hollander, Willard F. - bird navigation; Yale University. H”lldobler, Bert - Harvard University; social insect communication. Holtfreter, Johannes - University of Rochester; bird neuro-anatomy. Hooper, Emmet T. - University of Michigan. Hooper, John H. D. - bat banding; horseshoe bats; England. Hooper, Winifred M. (Mrs. J.H.D.) - bats; caves; National Speleological Society. Hopkins, Carl D. - Cornell University. Hornung, J. L. - photographs for textbook; Walter Hervey Junior College; McGraw-Hill Publishers. House of Travel - Africa travel. Howard, Robert C. - bat orientation; Bell Telephone Labs. Howe, I. A. (Mrs. Edward F.) - bats in house. Howell, Arthur H. - American Society of Mammalogists; bat gender ratio. Howell, Donna J. - Princeton University; Office of Naval Research; bat conference. Hubbard, J. C. - bat sound receptors; Catholic University. Hubbard, Ruth H. - National Research Council reference. Hubendick, B. - Naturhistoriska Riksmuseet, Sweden; bird sound recording. Huddy, Robert C. - homing pigeons. Huff, Jane N. - Michigan State University; mouse sound recording equipment. Hunt, F. R. - National Research Council of Canada; bird-aircraft collisions. Hunt, F. V. - Harvard University Underwater Sound Lab; echolocation. Huntington, Charles E. - bird radio-tracking; equipment loans; see also Projects-Bowdoin Scientific Station; Kent Island; Bowdoin College;. Huntsman, A. G. - bird and fish homing; Fisheries Research Board of Canada. Hutchins, Mrs. - housing issues. Hutchins, Louis - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute; Cornell University. Hutchins, Ross E. - beetles swimming; Mississippi State College. Hutchinson, G. E. - Yale University. Hutchinson, Ronald - Senator Proxmire; Morton Schwartz; Golden Fleece Awards; Office of Naval Research; Fund to Protect Scholars from Defamation.
  - Hall, John S. (Box 5, Folder 46)
    Albright College; Trinidad; Simla; Beebe Tropical Station; bat banding; University of Illinois; University of Massachusetts; see also Projects-Bat Banding
  - Harrison, Jean (Box 5, Folder 47)
    Wellesley College; UCLA; bird tracking; DRG research associate
  - Harvard University Biological Laboratories - General (Box 5, Folder 48)
    George Bartholomew; Ernst Mayr; Roger Sperry; Books in Biology series; McGeorge Bundy; Biological Council; Paul Mangelsdorf; Simonds Steel Mills; George Wald
  - Harvard University Biological Laboratories - Operations (Box 5, Folder 49)
    NY Zoological Society; Elizabeth Thompson Science Fund; WGBH; Israel Institute for Biological Research; Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT); Shuer Brothers; Movie Lab Film Laboratories; J. C. Nicholls, Jr. bat supplier
  - Harvard University, Fatigue Laboratory (Box 5, Folder 50)
    General Electric Co.; James V. Bradley; Aero-Medical Laboratory; Sid Robinson; Kent Island; David Bruce Gill; Armored Medical Research Laboratory; World War II; insulated clothing; William Forbes; Ed Folk; National Institute of Health; see also Karl Lashley
  - Harvard University - Personal (Box 5, Folder 51)
    Society of Fellows; academic record
  - Hatch, Jeremy J. (Box 6, Folder 52)
    Duke University; Rockefeller University; National Institute of Health; ornithology; Pickvance, T. J.; University of Massachusetts; Beebe Tropical Research Station
  - Heppner, Frank (Box 6, Folder 53)
    University of Rhode Island; rockets; cloud detector
  - Hitchcock, Harold B. (Box 6, Folder 54)
    Middlebury College; University of Western Ontario; bird homing; Office of Naval Research; American Philosophical Society; The Auk; Max Planck Institut; Gustav Kramer; Bates College; Thompson Science Fund; Jeffries Wyman; Signal Corps; see also Projects-Bat Banding
  - Hock, Raymond J. (Box 6, Folder 55)
    University of Arizona; Point Barrow, Alaska; Arctic Health Research Center; Arctic Aeromedical Laboratory; University of Iowa; G. Edgar Folk; Cornell University; Point Barrow
  - Huyck Preserve (Box 6, Folder 56)
    also see Projects - Huyck Preserve; Thomas Ordway, MD; bird migration; bat banding; Jean Piatt; Robert Dalgleish
  - I and J (Box 6, Folder 57)
    Ilyichev, Valery - International Congress of Ornithologists. Ingman, Bob - U.S. Army Air Base; Wendover Field, Utah. Institute Fur den Wissenschaftlichen Film - film. Iriarte, Noel Fco. Leyva - bats; in Spanish. Irwin, Howard S. - New York Botanical Garden; Millbrook, NY. Isaacs, John D. - Scripps Institution of Oceanography; H. M. Johnson; Arctic Aero-Medical Lab; Alaska; Ladd Air Force Base. Isenberg, Martin - bats. Jackson, H. H. T. - U.S. National Museum; Southwest War Work. Jackson, V. W. - bats; Chautauqua, NY. Jacobs, Danny Odell - Harvard University; Rockefeller University. Jacoby, V. E. - reprints. Jaffe, Bernard M. - SUNY, Brooklyn. Jameson, E. W. - University of California, Davis; Cornell University; bat echolocation and anatomy. Jansen, Jan - Universitetet I Oslo, Norway; Jens Hall; bat hearing. Jaynes, Julian - Princeton University; animal psychology. Jen, Phillip H. S. - University of Missouri; Goethe Universitat; bat echolocation; equipment; Washington University; Lipmanova; Pollak. Jennings, William L. - Florida Board of Health; rabies; bat ultrasound. Jensen, Mary Jo - bats; Huyck Preserve. Jepsen, Glenn L. - Princeton University; bat fossil. Johnson Controls, Ltd. - M.W. Okinicha; harm to animals from microwave radiation. Johnson, Fred H. - Alaska; University of Illinois; Cornell University. Johnson, Martin W. - bat echolocation; Scripps Institute of Oceanography; Naval Radio Sound Lab. Johnson, Roger - caves; Massachusetts. Johnston, James W., Jr. - radio-carbon tags; Georgetown University School of Medicine. Jolly, Alison - Peter Marler; Rockefeller University; Sussex University. Jones, R. L. - bats in house. Judd, A. Bradford - Cornell University; King Fahad Ign Saud Abdul Aziz; Saudi Arabia; Harvard University.
  - Irving, Laurence (Box 6, Folder 58)
    Arctic Health Research Center; Office of Naval Research; Barrow, Alaska; Swarthmore College; bird metabolism; Woods Hole
  - Ka-Kl (Box 6, Folder 59)
    Kaiser, Neva (Mrs. Walter) - animal thinking. Kalmbach, E. R. - Howard T. Odum; Yale University; bird migration; U.S. Wildlife Research Laboratory, Colorado. Karplus, Martin - see also Arctic Research Laboratory; California Institute of Technology; Bird Migration. Katsuki, Yafuji - Tokyo Medical and Dental University. Kavanau, J. Lee - University of California; genetics. Kearns, Mary H. (Mrs. William) - bats in house. Keester, Ross - University of Chicago; bat detector equipment. Keiser, David S. - bat and pigeon homing. Kelemen, George - Bat Larynxes; Harvard Medical School; Massachusetts Eye and Ear Infirmary; Mosher Lab. Kellerman, Henry - Postgraduate Center for Mental Health. Kelley, Edmund S. - Duxbury Yacht Club. Kellogg, Paul P. - Cornell University; sound recordings. Kennedy, John S. - Imperial College Field Station; bird and insect orientation; Woods Hole. Kenney, Robert - ultrasonics. Kerridge, David - University of Victoria; Hagmeier. Kiester, A. Ross - University of Chicago; bat detector;. King, John - Michigan State University; mice behavior. Kinne, Otto - Biologische Anstalt Helgoland. Kirk, George L. - bats; caves. Kittredge, Henry C. - St. Paul's School; Kent Island;. Kiviat, Erik - Bard College; bat survey. Kleerekoper, Herman - Hamilton College; McMaster University; physiology and orientation; Office of Naval Research; S. R. Galler. Kleese, Deborah - rat communication; ultrasonics; Lynette Geyer. Kleinholtz, Lewis H. - Reed College; bats; Woods Hole. Klemm, W. R. - Texas A and M; book chapter. Klopfer, Peter H. - Yale University; tree swallow echo-location.
  - Kn-Ky (Box 6, Folder 60)
    Knight, Howard - Weber College; bird navigation. Knipper, Helmut - Technischen Hochschule Darmstadt; birds. Koch, Arthur L. - Indiana University; turtle orientation. Koehler, Glen - bat tragus. Kohls, Glen M. - National Institute of Health; Montana; ticks on bats. Kolb, Anton - Gesamthochschule; Germany; insect sounds. Koller, Alice - National Humanities Center; animal communication; ethology. Korsmeyer, F. B. - bat echolocation. Kosciusko, Kris - Bates College; Millbrook, NY; Rockefeller University Center for Field Research in Ecology and Ethology; employee. Kovasznay, Leslie S. G. - Johns Hopkins University; equipment; bat ultrasonic sounds. Kramer, Gustav - Max Planck Institut; Ernst Mayr; bird directionals. Kreithen, Melvin L. - Cornell University; pigeon homing; University of Pittsburgh. Krinsky, Susan G. - Harvard University. Kronenberg, Fredi - Stanford University; mammalian scent making; Katherine Ralls. Krzanowski, Adam - Poland; chiropterology. Kuhl, Patricia K. - University of Washington; speech perception. Kuhring, M. S. - National Research Council of Canada; bird hazards to aircraft; Jacoby. Kulzer, Erwin - Universitat Tubingen; bat larynx. Kunz, Thomas H. - Boston University; monitoring bat flight; Trinidad; Bradbury; U.S. Army Night Vision Laboratory. Kyllingstad, Henry C. - Fort Yates, North Dakota; bird banding. Kyshakevych, R. Y. - oilbirds; Trinidad; Peace Corps; Colombia.
  - Keeton, William T. (Box 6, Folder 61)
    Cornell University; bird orientation
  - Kennedy, Donald (Box 6, Folder 62)
    Woods Hole; National Science Foundation; Syracuse University; frog and fish retina; Stanford University; Harvard Club; Syracuse University
  - Konishi, Mark (Box 7, Folder 63)
    Venezuela; oilbirds; Princeton University; Trinidad; W. H. Phelps, Jr.; ethology; Cal-Tech; Chillagoe
  - Konstantinov, Aleksei (Box 7, Folder 64)
    Indiana University; Leningrad State University; James Simmons; Rod Suthers
  - La-Le (Box 7, Folder 65)
    Lack, David - Oxford University; bird orientation and sounds. Lackey, Catharine (Mrs. Walter) - bats and articles. Ladenburg, Rudolf - Princeton University; Sound wave photos. Lagemann, R. T. - Emory University; Galambos. Gressley, Gene M. - University of Wyoming archives. Landau, Barbara - blind children's echolocation; University of Pennsylvania; Henry Gleitman. Lange and Springer - in German. Langerholc, John - musical harmony and bat echolocation. Langmeier, Dave - insect sounds; Haile's Cave; RCA Manufacturing co.. Lansa, Renee (Mrs. Conrad) - bats in house. Larkin, Ron - Illinois Natural History Survey Division; Air Force work; Woods Hole; Fourier transform; Gould; Mueller; honeybees. Kuhl, Patricia K. - University of Washington; speech perception. Larsen, Richard J. - Vanderbilt University; echolocation data. Latham, William H. - Boy Scouts; bat repellents. Laven, Hannes - in German; A.O. Gross, Bowdoin College. Lavender, Tony - sound recordings; see also James Simmons. Leader, Bob - Rockefeller University Laboratory of Animal Behavior; Bill Conway; Gandal; NY Zoological Park. Leavitt, Kent - Innisfree; Stillman and Cagney Estates; Millbrook, NY. Lederberg, Joshua - Stanford University; Richard and Martha Furie; tropical fish; Marilyn Yodlowski. Lee, Edward M., Jr. - bats in house. Lee, James B. - bird migration; Eleonora D'Arms. Leger, Daniel - University of Nebraska; squirrel alarm calls. Leghorn, Kenneth - Phillips Exeter Academy. Lehman, A. Thomas - bats; Union Mutual Life Insurance Company. Leitner, Philip - St. Mary's College; bat altitude; Beebe Tropical Research Station. Leonard, Christiana M. - working paper on women at Rockefeller University; John Raper. Leppik, Elmar E. - Augustana College; pollinating insects. Levi, Wendell M. - The Pigeon; bird orientation. Levine, Elizabeth - Amherst College; bat ovulation. Levine, Jacob "Jack" - Human blindness; Old Farms Convalescent Hospital; soldiers. Lewellen, John - bird navigation; Saturday Evening Post. Lewis, Glenn E. - National Center for Atmospheric Research Computing Facility; computer development. Lewis, Harrison F. - Canada Department of Mines and Resources. Lewis, John - McGill University; bird orientation.
  - Li-Ly (Box 7, Folder 66)
    Licklider, J.C.R. - MIT; Thiessen; Shaw; Journal of Acoustical Society of America. Lidicker, William Z., Jr. - University of California, Berkeley; bat DNA. Lien, Jon - Memorial University of Newfoundland; whale recordings; Chris Spencer; Roger Payne; Peter Tyack. Lillestrand, Robert - General Mills Research Laboratory; Birds and wind currents. Lincoln, Frederick C. - U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. Lindauer, Martin - Universitat Wurzburg; in German. Linhart, Samuel B. - U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service; bats and rabies. Lippman, Louis - Western Washington State College; bat navigation. Little, Luther - Bat banding; California. Llewellyn, Leonard M. - Virginia Polytechnic Institute; bat banding. Lloyd, James E. - University of Florida; sound equipment. Lockard, Robert B. - University of Washington; textbook. Lord, Frederick T. - bird homing. Lord, Rexford D. - Centro Panamericano de Zoonosis; Argentina; bats. Loregnard, Robert - I.M. Goodbody; University College of the West Indies; Trinidad;. Lorenz, Konrad - Max Planck Institut. Losee, Margaret - State University at New Paltz, NY; caves. Lowery, George H., Jr. - Louisiana State University; bird navigation. Luce, E. S. - Custer Battlefield National Monument; bats in buildings. Lyman, Charles - Harvard Medical School; Museum of Comparative Zoology. Lynch, F.C.C - National Development Bureau Canada.
  - Lashley, K.S. (Box 7, Folder 67)
    Yerkes Laboratories; bats and blind veterans; birds; radar; Bonaventure Island; Arctic Research Laboratory; Office of Naval Research; Point Barrow, Alaska; homing; von Frisch; Florida State University; Harvard Fatigue Laboratory; Darryl Bruce; Henry Yeagley
  - Lecture Requests (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Lipmanova, Eugenia (Janna) (Box 7, Folder 69)
    Konstantinov; Laboratoire de Spectronomie Moleculaire; Paris; Leningrad State University; USSR Space Training Center; University of Texas; George Pollak; refugee scholar; Jewish; Boris Lipmanov; National Institute of Health
  - Ma-Me (Box 7, Folder 70)
    MacDonald, Alister - University of NC, Wilmington; Woods Hole; echo fish; Office of Naval Research. Mahaley, M. S., Jr. - Cave Temperatures; North Carolina. Malins, Donald - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; Northwest and Alaska Fisheries Center; lipids and sound. Mandriota, Frank J. - Hunter College; psychology; pilot. Manery, Jeanne F. - Canada; National Defense Research Lab; radiation. Manion, Bruce L. - Pretrels; Alpha Helix; New Guinea; San Francisco State University. Marchetti, John W. - birds and radar; Air Materiel Command; Cambridge Field Station. Marler, Peter - Rockefeller University; birds; airplanes; 2 color slides. Marley, A. A. J. - McGill University; neurophysiology of echolocation. Marsh, Elizabeth Redfield (aunt) - Stockton State College. Marshall, John - Peabody Museum; Harvard University; Film. Marshall, Wade H. - National Institute of Health; animal suffering. Martin, Edward - Texas A and I; recording equipment. Martin, Robert L. - University of Maine; Bat Research News. Mason, A. G. - bird migration routes; Thomas H. Mason and Sons. Mason, C. Russell - Massachusetts Audubon Society; airplane study of birds. Mason, Edwin A. - bat and gull banding. Massachusetts General Hospital - Dr. Lurie; Miss Linden; bat anatomy; Mosher Laboratory. Masters, Gene P. - MIT; echolocation. Masters, Mitch - University of Oregon; bat sonar tracking; James Simmons; Anne Moffat. Matuschke, Gunter - bat photo. May, Les - animal sound equipment; Scotland. Mayr, Ernst - American Museum of Natural History; bird banding; Evolution. McCleary, James A. - Northern Illinois University. McCormick, James G. - Naval Undersea Warfare Center; porpoise hearing; Princeton University. McCoy, Dr. - Paper for Walker Prize. McCue, J. J. G. - MIT; Lincoln Lab; signal processing. McGill, Thomas E. - Williams College; Comparative Psychology. McIlhenny, E. A. - homing birds; Avery Island, LA. McIntyre, Judy - University of Minnesota; Kytoons, Kite balloons for bird sounds. McLean, Noel B. - Atlantic Foundation; Woods Hole; George Ruggieri; Osborn Laboratories. McMahon, Senator Brien - atomic energy control bill; Manhattan Project. McMillan, Ann - musician; recorded animal sounds; New York City Urban Corps. Medway, Lord and Lady - University of Malaya. Mellgren, Roger L. - University of Oklahoma; animal cognition book chapter. Menaker, Michael - University of Oregon; University of Texas, Austin; James Simmons; H. F. Guggenheim Foundation. Menaker, Walter - smoking addiction; Rockefeller University; Dr. Schachter; lunar periodicity. Mer, G. G. - Hebrew University; Malaria Research Station, Palestine; bats. Messler, Frank J. - ultrasonic equipment. Meteorological Research Unit - England; instruments on balloons.
  - Mi-My (Box 8, Folder 71)
    Milkman, Roger - University of Iowa; neurobiology. Miller, Howard A. - birds and high frequency sounds. Gobert, Andrew - Cornell University; pigeons; George Feliu. Miller, Mal - School of Aviation Medicine; bat diseases. Miller, Mary - bats in house. Miller, Richard S. - Colorado State University; cowbird migration. Milhovic, Karuche ? - Yugoslavia. Minnich, D. E. - University of Minnesota; Donald Kennedy; Timothy Goldsmith. Mitchell, H. P. - bats for orchard use. Mitchell, M. H. - Canada; fishing bats. Miyahara, Jirokichi - in Japanese; bird orientation. Mock, John E. - State of Georgia Science Advisory Council; kytoons; equipment. Moffett, J. A. - Whitehall Foundation; RU Dept. Biology Advisory Council. Mohler, Irvin C. - American Institute of Biological Sciences. Moldenke, Harold N. - Union County, NJ Park Commission; Doubleday children's book. Molini, Lt. Antino F. - bats; Puerto Rico. Moller, Aage R. - Karolinska Institutet; hearing exhibit; conferences. Moore, A. D. - University of Michigan; animal energy. Moore, Bruce R. - Dalhousie University; bat film. Moore, Clifford B. - Trailside Museum; zoology textbook. Moore, Joseph C. - Everglades National Park; manatee; bats in Florida. Moore, Mrs. Peter L. - animal navigation; crab "radar"; Fortune magazine. Moore, Terris - University of Alaska; bird navigation. Moorehead, Warren K. - Phillips Academy. Moorman, F. Lander - proving God's existence. Morell, L. E. - bat radar; recording equipment. Morse, Douglass H. - University of Michigan; theory of pecten. Morton, Eugene S. - Smithsonian Institution; bird sound recording. Morton, John M. - bats carrying bedbugs; Philippines; Missouri House of Representatives. Moulton, James W. - Bowdoin College; Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution; Office of Naval Research; fish sound production; Lalor Foundation; Kent Island. Moynihan, Martin - University Museum, Oxford; N. Tinbergen; Gustav Swanson; Cornell University. Moysey, Bob - Saipan bats. Mulcahy, Frances - Visit 4th graders. Muller, Fredrik A. - University of Virginia; bat flight patterns. Munroe, Thomas G. - caving, Buffalo, NY; General Cable Co.. Murman, Mrs. Sydney P. - bats in house. Murray, Bertram G., Jr. - Cornell University; bird navigation. Myers, Richard F. - University of Missouri; U.S. Army. Myres, M. T. - University of Alberta; bird orientation.
  - Markl, Hubert (Box 8, Folder 72)
    Beebe Tropical Research Station, Trinidad; Indiana University; Zoologisches Institut, Frankfurt, Germany; Zoologisches Institut der Technischen Hochschule; Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology; Alpha Helix
  - Matthews, G.V.T. (Box 8, Folder 73)
    University of Cambridge; bird navigation; Wildfowl Trust
  - McNab, Brian (Box 8, Folder 74)
    University of Wisconsin; echolocation; Beebe Tropical Research Station; Trinidad; Universidade de Sao Paulo; Rod Suthers; NY Zoological Society; Alpha Helix
  - Meyer, Otto (Box 8, Folder 75)
    Pigeon Breeding and Training Center; Donald Gordon
  - Michener, Martin C. (Box 8, Folder 76)
    pigeon tracking by airplane; Charles Walcott; Education Development Center
  - Mislin, H (Box 8, Folder 77)
    Universitat Basel, Switzerland; Experientia; Cameroon expedition
  - Mohr, Charles E. (Box 8, Folder 78)
    Audubon Center; Rockefeller Foundation fellowship; Reading Public Museum; bat homing; bat banding; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia; P. J. Bels
  - Mohres, Franz Peter (Box 8, Folder 79)
    Dr. Schnitzler; Beebe Station, Trinidad; John Nelson; Alpha Helix; New Guinea; Zoologiches Institut; see Galler, Office of Naval Research; Sid Galler
  - Morse, Philip W. "Pete" (Box 8, Folder 80)
    Cleveland Plain Dealer; Bowdoin Scientific Station; friend; bat banding
  - Mueller, Helmut C. (Box 8, Folder 81)
    University of Wisconsin; bat conditioning; University of North Carolina
  - N (Box 8, Folder 82)
    Nachtigall, Werner - Zoologisches Institut der Universitat des Saarlandes; Germany; birds; infrared viewers. Narins, Peter - University of California, LA; frog sounds; geophones. National Audubon Society - bird-airplane collision. National Educational Alliance - payment dispute. National Research Council - Committee on Biosphere Effects of... .Radiation; U.S. Navy. National Speleological Society - membership; LeRoy Foote; Delmar Wildlife Research Center. Natuschke, Gunther - Germany; bat bibliography. Nelson, John - University of Queensland; Monash University; Alpha Helix; Trinidad; New Guinea; Australia; echolocation; instruments; Mohres. Nelson, Theodora - bird banding. Nesbit, William - flashlight apparatus; animal photography. Neuhaus, Walter - Universitat Hamburg; bird sound measurement. Neuweiler, Gerhard - Zoophysiologisches Institut der Universitat Tobingen; Germany. Newbury Lumber and Building Materials - bats in lumberyard. Newcomer, W. Stanley - Oklahoma A and M; equipment. New Hampshire Nature Camp - Jarvis Hadley; Barnum Museum, Tufts College;. Newton, R.G. - England; bird navigation. New York Academy of Sciences - membership; see also Publishers. Nichols, David Gelston - bats; Groton friend. Nicholls, David G. - Geelong C of E Grammar School; Australia; tracking bird migration with Doppler and satellites. Nickel, Jim - Oklahoma physics teacher. Nielsen, Erik Tetens - Molslaboratoriet, Denmark; American Museum of Natural History; Archbold Expeditions; Office of Naval Research; Florida State Board of Health; Sherwood Hammock Biological Laboratory. Nippon Television Network - Toshio Nakazawa. Nisbet, Ian C. T. - Massachusetts Audubon Society; bird navigation. Noland, Lowell E. - University of Wisconsin. Nordmach, Jan - Karolinska Institutet; Sweden; echo-location. Norris, Kenneth - Marineland of the Pacific; Office of Naval Research; Dody Dunning; Lorenz; Sidney Galler; echo-location; University of California, Los Angeles; Scripps Institution of Oceanography; Norris Nausea Machine; Makapuu Oceanic Center; Hawaii. Nortan, Arthur H. - Portland Society of Natural History; Maine. Northington, Captain Page - Department of Navy; bird homing; streptomycin. Novick, Alvin - Harvard University hospital; Yale University. Nowicki, Stephen - bird communication; Rockefeller University. Nuttall Ornithological Club - Oscar Root; Brooks School; Museum of Comparative Zoology; New England Museum of Natural History; Wendell Taber;. Nyquist, Alfred W. - Caves; Finger Lakes region of New York; O. D. von Engeln; Cornell University.
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box 9, Folder 83)
    Orson Eaton; Secretary of the Interior; C. B. Morton; Bureau of Sports Fisheries and Wildlife
  - National Geographic Society (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 9, Folder 85)
    evaluation of proposals; Agency for International Development; India
  - New York Zoological Society (Box 9, Folder 86)
    see also Emsley, Michael; membership
  - O (Box 9, Folder 87)